SAMANTHA SHARFF

Camden, ME | SamanthaLeeC@gmail.com | 603-617-6940 | github.com/SamSharff | linkedin.com/in/samsharff

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Software engineer who thrives in the space where the public and tech intersect. With boots-on-the-ground experience as a librarian and social service worker, my work as a technologist is motivated by a deep commitment and responsibility to the user, as well as a natural eye for detail.

SKILLS

Technical: Ruby, Rails, Vue.js, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, PostgreSQL, Git, GitHub, APIs, Testing,

Pair-Programming, Object-Oriented Programming, Bootstrap

Additional: Member: Technologists for the Public Good; Notary Public

EDUCATION

Actualize Coding Bootcamp | Certificate in Full Stack Web Development

Jan 2022 - May 2022

 A four-month full-stack web development bootcamp. Core technologies included Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, and Vue.js. Special emphasis on API-driven development, version control with git, professional tooling, team collaboration, and continual learning.

University of Missouri | Coursework towards M.A. in Library and Information Science University of New Hampshire | B.A. in Theatre

EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant (Web Development) | Actualize Coding Bootcamp

Jun 2022 - Sep 2022

- Facilitate student learning of a range of languages, platforms, frameworks, and technical skills in live, intensive online classroom environment
- Lead virtual office hours for cohort of 14 students
- Evaluate student progress in communication and partnership with lead software instructor

Office Manager | Rockland Congregational Church

Aug 2020 - Feb 2022

- Managed daily operations for 120+ member church, overseeing facilities and collaborating with leadership, members, and committees to keep things efficient and clean
- Modernized all business operations by digitizing records, automating manual processes via software, and documenting and training others in best technology practices to support the onboarding of future employees

AP Finance Contractor | Knox County Homeless Coalition

Apr 2020 - Oct 2020

- Implemented and trained multiple departments on automation practices, data conventions, and digital platforms and software for an organization that was previously using manual record keeping
- Tracked accurate accounts payable, credit card expense documentation, and data points related to state housing grant expenditures to support the continued proper administration of emergency money for sheltering vulnerable populations during the pandemic

Library Professional | Rockport Public Library, Norwich Public Library

Aug 2014 - Jun 2020

- Gained deep understanding of various ILS software, platforms, and modules, training and guiding others regularly
- Troubleshot technology issues for users daily, identifying the source of errors and providing solutions

Co-owner & Communications Contractor | Cobblestone Communications

Aug 2016 - Aug 2020

- Produced copy, web design, social media, e-newsletter, and photographic services for nonprofits and small businesses by taking time to understand client goals and translating them into marketable materials
- Trained local business and nonprofit leaders on how to access and update their website designs and troubleshoot technical problems as they arose

Lead Caseworker | Episcopal Service Corps.

Sep 2012 - Jun 2013

- Evaluated client eligibility for requested services based on level of need and current available budget
- Partnered with organization Director to track and manage grants of up to \$50,000, maximizing benefit to clients while maintaining compliance with grant stipulations
- Promoted from intern to lead caseworker within three months of beginning service term

CERTIFICATIONS

Notary Public | State of Maine

Jan 2019

Public Librarian Certificate | Maine State Library

Intro to Data Analysis Certificate | IBM, Coursera.org

April 2017

Mar 2021